Yu Gong slandered the sovereign and father
Юй Гун клеветал на государя
Deserves death ten thousand times
заслуживает смерти
But Father is benevolent
Но отец милосерден
If you could spare his life
если можете простить ему смерть
And exile him
сослать его
To the frontier
сослать на границу
Would be a good thing
это будет благородный поступок
First
Вопервых
It can warn the world
можно предостеречь людей
Not to despise the court's authority
не смейте пренебрегать властью двора
Second
Вовторых
It can show all the people
можно показать всему народу
Father's generous treatment of loyal and righteous men
покажет милость отца к верным людям
As the saying goes
Как говорится
If crow eggs are not destroyed
пока гнездо ворона не разрушено
Then phoenixes will gather
фениксы не прилетят
If slander is not punished with death
за клевету не казнят
Then
тогда
Good counsel will flow
добрые советы не иссякнут
Second son
Второй сын
The principles in these books
книжная мудрость
Can't be applied to everything
не всегда применима
I also want to be a wise ruler for the ages
Я тоже хотел бы быть мудрым правителем на века
But
Но
Our family has only been stable in the south for a few years
Наша семья лишь недавно укрепилась на юге
So many great families are watching us
Столько знатных кланов наблюдают за нами  я не имею права ошибаться
I
я
Cannot make mistakes
нельзя ошибаться
Killing him
Казнить его
May not be the act of a wise ruler
может и не поступок мудрого правителя
But if I don't kill him
но если не казню
In the future
впредь
Anyone will dare to recklessly discuss court affairs
все начнут вольно обсуждать политику